corresponding to pressure points on the human body. Its surface, as in nature, varies its functionality not by adding another material or another assembly, but by continuously and delicately varying material property. But is nature ideal? Are there no parts in nature? I wasn't raised in a religious Jewish home, but when I was young, my grandmother used to tell me stories from the Hebrew Bible, and one of them stuck with me and came to define much of what I care about. As she recounts: "On the third day of Creation, God commands the Earth to grow a fruit-bearing fruit tree." For this first fruit tree, there was to be no differentiation between trunk, branches, leaves and fruit. The whole tree was a fruit. Instead, the land grew trees that have bark and stems and flowers. The land created a world made of parts. I often ask myself, "What would design be like if objects were made of a single part? Would we return to a better state of creation?" So we looked for that biblical material, that fruit-bearing fruit tree kind of material, and we found it. The second-most abundant biopolymer on the planet is called chitin, and some 100 million tons of it are produced every year by organisms such as shrimps, crabs, scorpions and butterflies. We thought if we could tune its properties, we could generate structures that are multifunctional out of a single part. So that's what we did. We called Legal Seafood -- (Laughter) we ordered a bunch of shrimp shells, we grinded them and we produced chitosan paste. By varying chemical concentrations, we were able to achieve a wide array of properties -- from dark, stiff and opaque, to light, soft and transparent. In order to print the structures in large scale, we built a robotically controlled extrusion system with multiple nozzles. The robot would vary material properties on the fly and create these 12-foot-long structures made of a single material, 100 percent recyclable. When the parts are ready, they're left to dry and find a form naturally upon contact with air. So why are we still designing with plastics? The air bubbles that were a byproduct of the printing process were used to contain photosynthetic microorganisms that first appeared on our planet 3.5 billion year ago, as we learned yesterday. Together with our collaborators at Harvard and MIT, we embedded bacteria that were genetically engineered to rapidly capture carbon from the atmosphere and convert it into sugar. For the first time, we were able to generate structures that would seamlessly transition from beam to mesh, and if scaled even larger, to windows. A fruit-bearing fruit tree. Working with an ancient material, one of the first lifeforms on the planet, plenty of water and a little bit of synthetic biology, we were able to transform a structure made of shrimp shells into an architecture that behaves like a tree. And here's the best part: for objects designed to biodegrade, put them in the sea, and they will nourish marine life; place them in soil, and they will help grow a tree. The setting for our next exploration using the same design principles was the solar system. We looked for the possibility of creating life-sustaining clothing for interplanetary voyages. To do that, we needed to contain bacteria and be able to control their flow. So like the periodic table, we came up with our own table of the elements: new lifeforms that were computationally grown, additively manufactured and biologically augmented. I like to think of synthetic biology as liquid alchemy, only instead of transmuting precious metals, you're synthesizing new biological functionality inside very small channels. It's called microfluidics. We 3D-printed our own channels in order to control the flow of these liquid bacterial cultures. In our first piece of clothing, we combined two microorganisms. The first is cyanobacteria. It lives in our oceans and in freshwater ponds. And the second, E. coli, the bacterium that inhabits the human gut. One converts light into sugar, the other consumes that sugar and produces biofuels useful for the built environment. Now, these two microorganisms never interact in nature. In fact, they never met each other. They've been here, engineered for the first time, to have a relationship inside a piece of clothing. Think of it as evolution not by natural selection, but evolution by design. In order to contain these relationships, we've created a single channel that resembles the digestive tract, that will help flow these bacteria and alter their function along the way. We then started growing these channels on the human body, varying material properties according to the desired functionality. Where we wanted more photosynthesis, we would design more transparent channels. This wearable digestive system, when it's stretched end to end, spans 60 meters. This is half the length of a football field, and 10 times as long as our small intestines. And here it is for the first time unveiled at TED -- our first photosynthetic wearable, liquid channels glowing with life inside a wearable clothing. (Applause) Thank you. Mary Shelley said, "We are unfashioned creatures, but only half made up." What if design could provide that other half? What if we could create structures that would augment living matter? What if we could create personal microbiomes that would scan our skins, repair damaged tissue and sustain our bodies? Think of this as a form of edited biology. This entire collection, Wanderers, that was named after planets, was not to me really about fashion per se, but it provided an opportunity to speculate about the future of our race on our planet and beyond, to combine scientific insight with lots of mystery and to move away from the age of the machine to a new age of symbiosis between our bodies, the microorganisms that we inhabit, our products and even our buildings. I call this material ecology. To do this, we always need to return back to nature. By now, you know that a 3D printer prints material in layers. You also know that nature doesn't. It grows. It adds with sophistication. This silkworm cocoon, for example, creates a highly sophisticated architecture, a home inside which to metamorphisize. No additive manufacturing today gets even close to this level of sophistication. It does so by combining not two materials, but two proteins in different concentrations. One acts as the structure, the other is the glue, or the matrix, holding those fibers together. And this happens across scales. The silkworm first attaches itself to the environment -- it creates a tensile structure -- and it then starts spinning a compressive cocoon. Tension and compression, the two forces of life, manifested in a single material. In order to better understand how this complex process works, we glued a tiny earth magnet to the head of a silkworm, to the spinneret. We placed it inside a box with magnetic sensors, and that allowed us to create this 3-dimensional point cloud and visualize the complex architecture of the silkworm cocoon. However, when we placed the silkworm on a flat patch, not inside a box, we realized it would spin a flat cocoon and it would still healthily metamorphisize. So we started designing different environments, different scaffolds, and we discovered that the shape, the composition, the structure of the cocoon, was directly informed by the environment. Silkworms are often boiled to death inside their cocoons, their silk unraveled and used in the textile industry. We realized that designing these templates allowed us to give shape to raw silk without boiling a single cocoon. (Applause) They would healthily metamorphisize, and we would be able to create these things. So we scaled this process up to architectural scale. We had a robot spin the template out of silk, and we placed it on our site. We knew silkworms migrated toward darker and colder areas, so we used a sun path diagram to reveal the distribution of light and heat on our structure. We then created holes, or apertures, that would lock in the rays of light and heat, distributing those silkworms on the structure. We were ready to receive the caterpillars. We ordered 6,500 silkworms from an online silk farm. And after four weeks of feeding, they were ready to spin with us. We placed them carefully at the bottom rim of the scaffold, and as they spin they pupate, they mate, they lay eggs, and life begins all over again -- just like us but much, much shorter. Bucky Fuller said that tension is the great integrity, and he was right. As they spin biological silk over robotically spun silk, they give this entire pavilion its integrity. And over two to three weeks, 6,500 silkworms spin 6,500 kilometers. In a curious symmetry, this is also the length of the Silk Road. The moths, after they hatch, produce 1.5 million eggs. This could be used for 250 additional pavilions for the future. So here they are, the two worldviews. One spins silk out of a robotic arm, the other fills in the gaps. If the final frontier of design is to breathe life into the products and the buildings around us, to form a two-material ecology, then designers must unite these two worldviews. Which brings us back, of course, to the beginning. Here's to a new age of design, a new age of creation, that takes us from a nature-inspired design to a design-inspired nature, and that demands of us for the first time that we mother nature. Thank you. (Applause) Thank you very much. Thank you.
correspondiendo a los puntos de presión en el cuerpo humano. Su superficie, como en la naturaleza, varía su funcionalidad no mediante la adición de otro material u otro ensamblaje, sino variando continuamente y delicadamente la propiedad material. Pero ¿es la naturaleza ideal? ¿No hay partes en la naturaleza? No me crié en un hogar judío religioso, pero cuando era joven, mi abuela me contaba historias de la Biblia hebrea, y uno de ellas se me quedó y llegó a definir mucho de lo que me importa. Como ella relata: "En el tercer día de la Creación, Dios manda a la Tierra hacer crecer un árbol frutal cargado de fruta". Para ese primer árbol frutal, no habría ninguna diferencia entre tronco, ramas, hojas y frutos. Todo el árbol era una fruta. En cambio, la tierra hizo crecer árboles con ramas, corteza, tallos y flores. La tierra creó un mundo hecho de partes. A menudo me pregunto, "¿Cuál sería el diseño si los objetos se hicieran de una sola pieza? ¿Volveríamos a un mejor estado de la creación? " Así que buscamos que el material bíblico, el tipo de material del árbol frutal con frutas, y lo encontramos. El segundo biopolímero más abundante en el planeta se llama quitina, y unos 100 millones de toneladas se producen cada año por organismos como camarones, cangrejos, escorpiones y mariposas. Pensamos que si podíamos sintonizar sus propiedades, podríamos generar estructuras multifuncionales en una sola pieza. Así que eso es lo que hicimos. Lo llamamos marisco legal. (Risas) Pedimos un montón de cáscaras de camarón, las molimos y produjimos pasta de quitosano. Variando las concentraciones químicas, hemos podido lograr una amplia gama de propiedades, desde oscuro, duro y opaco, a la luz, suave y transparente. Para imprimir las estructuras a gran escala, se construyó un sistema con múltiples boquillas de extrusión controlado robóticamente. El robot podía variar las propiedades del material sobre la marcha y crear estas estructuras hechas de un solo material 3.5 m de largo, 100 % reciclable. Cuando las piezas están listas, se las deja secar para encontrar una forma natural al contacto con el aire. Así que ¿por qué seguimos diseñando con plástico? Las burbujas de aire que eran un subproducto del proceso de impresión se utilizaron para contener microorganismos fotosintéticos que aparecieron por primera vez en el planeta hace 3.5 mil millones años, como escuchamos ayer. Junto con nuestros colaboradores en Harvard y el MIT, incrustamos las bacterias diseñadas genéticamente para capturar rápidamente carbono de la atmósfera y convertirlo en azúcar. Por primera vez, hemos podido generar estructuras que hacen su transición sin problemas de viga a malla, y si se amplía aún más, a ventanas. Un árbol frutal cargado de fruta. Trabajar con un material antiguo, una de las primeras formas de vida en el planeta, con abundante agua y con un poco de biología sintética, hemos transformado una estructura hecha de cáscaras de camarón en una arquitectura que se comporta como un árbol. Y aquí está la mejor parte: para objetos diseñados para biodegradarse, puestos en el mar, alimentarán la vida marina; y colocados en el suelo, ayudarán a crecer un árbol. El ajuste para nuestra próxima exploración utilizando los mismos principios de diseño era el sistema solar. Buscamos la posibilidad de crear ropa para mantener la vida para los viajes interplanetarios. Para hacer eso, debemos dominar las bacterias y controlar su flujo. Así como la tabla periódica, hicimos nuestra propia mesa de elementos: nuevas formas de vida creadas computacionalmente, fabricadas de forma aditiva y aumentadas de forma biológica. Me gusta pensar en la biología sintética como la alquimia líquida, solo que en vez de transmutar metales preciosos, se sintetizan nuevas funcionalidades biológicas dentro de canales muy pequeños. Este campo se denomina microfluídica. Imprimimos nuestros propios canales 3D para controlar el flujo de estos cultivos bacterianos líquidos. En nuestra primera pieza de ropa, se combinaron dos microorganismos. El primero es la cianobacteria. Vive en nuestros océanos y en los estanques de agua dulce. Y el segundo, E. coli, la bacteria que habita en el intestino humano. Una convierte la luz en azúcar, la otra consume azúcar y produce biocombustibles útiles para el entorno construido. Pero estos dos microorganismos no interactúan en la naturaleza. De hecho, nunca se conocieron. Ellos están aquí, diseñados por primera vez, para tener una relación en una pieza de ropa. Piense en ello como evolución, no por selección natural, sino evolución por diseño. Para contener estas relaciones, hemos creado un único canal que se asemeja al tracto digestivo, que ayudará a que fluyan estas bacterias y a que alteren su función de camino. Entonces comenzamos hacer crecer esos canales en el cuerpo humano, variando las propiedades del material según la funcionalidad deseada. Si queríamos más fotosíntesis, diseñábamos canales más transparentes. Este sistema digestivo portable, cuando se estira de un extremo a otro, abarca 60 metros. Esta es la mitad de la longitud de un campo de fútbol, y 10 veces más que nuestro intestino delgado. Y aquí está, como primicia en TED, nuestra primera fotosintética portable, canales líquidos brillantes con vida dentro de la ropa. (Aplausos) Gracias. Mary Shelley dijo: "Somos criaturas pasadas de moda, solo la mitad está hecha." ¿Qué pasa si el diseño proporcionara la otra mitad? ¿Y si pudiéramos crear estructuras que aumentan la materia viva? ¿Y si pudiéramos crear microbiomas personales que escanearan nuestra piel, repararan el tejido dañado y sostuvieran nuestros cuerpos? Piense en esto como una forma de editar la biología. Toda esta colección "Trotamundos" lleva el nombre de los planetas, no era para mí muy moderna en sí, pero brindó la oportunidad de especular sobre el futuro de nuestra raza en nuestro planeta y más allá, combinar una visión científica con un montón de misterio y alejarse de la edad de la máquina hacia a una nueva era de la simbiosis entre nuestros cuerpos, los microorganismos que habitamos, nuestros productos e, incluso, nuestros edificios. Yo llamo a esto la ecología material. Para ello, siempre hay que volver a la naturaleza. Por ahora, se sabe que una impresora 3D imprime material en capas. También se sabe que la naturaleza no lo hace así. Crece. Añade con sofisticación. Este capullo del gusano, por ejemplo, crea una arquitectura altamente sofisticada, un hogar dentro del cual se metamorfosiza. La fabricación no aditiva se acerca a este nivel de sofisticación. Lo hace mediante la combinación no de dos materiales, sino de dos proteínas en diferentes concentraciones. Una actúa como estructura, la otra es el pegamento o la matriz, uniendo esas fibras entre sí. Y esto sucede a través de escalas. El gusano de seda primero se prende en el medio ambiente, crea una estructura de tensión, y luego comienza a hilar un capullo de compresión. La tensión y la compresión, las dos fuerzas de la vida, se manifiestan en un único material. Con el fin de comprender mejor cómo funciona este proceso complejo, pegamos un imán pequeño a la cabeza de un gusano de seda, a la hilera. Lo colocamos dentro de una caja con sensores magnéticos, y eso nos permitió crear esta nube de puntos en 3 dimensiones y visualizar la compleja arquitectura del capullo del gusano de seda. Sin embargo, al colocar el gusano de seda en un parche plano, no dentro de una caja, nos dimos cuenta de que hilaría un capullo plano y todavía metamorforsizar sanamente. Así que empezamos a diseñar diferentes entornos, diferentes andamios, y hemos descubierto que la forma, la composición, la estructura del capullo, se transmitía directamente por el medio ambiente. A menudo se hierven los gusanos de seda hasta la muerte dentro de sus capullos, su seda se deshace y se utiliza en la industria textil. Vimos que diseñando estas plantillas podíamos dar forma a la seda cruda sin hervir un solo capullo. (Aplausos) Se metamorfosizarían sanamente, y podríamos crear estas cosas. Así escalamos este proceso hasta la escala arquitectónica. Tuvimos un robot hilador haciendo plantillas de seda, y nos colocamos en nuestro sitio. Sabíamos que los gusanos de seda emigrado hacia zonas más oscuras y frías, por eso utilizamos un diagrama de ruta solar para revelar la distribución de la luz y el calor en nuestra estructura. Entonces creamos agujeros o aberturas, para bloquear los rayos de la luz y el calor, distribuyendo los gusanos de seda sobre la estructura. Estábamos preparados para recibir a las orugas. Pedimos 6500 gusanos de seda a una granja de seda en línea. Y después de alimentarlos 4 semanas, estaban preparados a hilar con nosotros. Las colocamos cuidadosamente en el borde inferior del andamio, y mientras hilaban, crisalizaban, se apareaban, ponían huevos, y la vida comienza de nuevo, como nosotros, pero mucho, mucho más corta. Bucky Fuller dijo que la tensión es la gran integridad, y tenía razón. Al hilar seda biológica sobre la seda hilada robóticamente, dan todo este pabellón su integridad. Y en poco más de dos o tres semanas, 6500 gusanos de seda tejen 6500 km. En una curiosa simetría, ésta es también la longitud de la ruta de la seda. Las polillas, después de la eclosión, producen 1.5 millones de huevos. Esto podría utilizarse para 250 pabellones adicionales en el futuro. Así que aquí están las dos visiones del mundo. Una hila seda mediante un brazo robótico, la otra llena vacíos. Si la última frontera del diseño es dar vida a los productos y a los edificios que nos rodean, para formar una ecología de dos materiales, los diseñadores deben unir estas dos visiones del mundo. Lo que nos lleva de vuelta, por supuesto, al principio. Aquí está a una nueva era de diseño, una nueva era de la creación, que nos lleva de un diseño inspirado en la naturaleza a una naturaleza inspirada en el diseño, que exige de nosotros, por primera vez, que nos hagamos cargo de la naturaleza. Gracias. (Aplausos) Muchas gracias. Gracias.